# **Brandon Caples**

#### SENIOR DIGITAL MARKETER

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com







I'm a self-motivated digital marketing professional with 10 years of experience working collaboratively and individually to move projects into production. I have personal experience with many marketing channels and concentrations, as well as a career working with a diverse set of products and services.

#### **SKILLS**

**EMAIL MARKETING** | Design and development, campaign strategy, segmentation, copywriting, Salesforce Marketing Cloud, ActiveCampaign, marketing automation, customer journeys, AMPscript

FRONTEND WEB DEVELOPMENT | HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, Timber/Twig, Ruby & Ruby on Rails, Liquid, WordPress, Shopify

**CONTENT MANAGEMENT** | SEO, content development, copywriting, PPC, social advertising, WordPress, Shopify, Squarespace, Wix

**ANALYTICS & DATA** | Excel, Google Analytics, reporting, SQL/SOQL, Google Tag Manager, JavaScript, data analysis

GRAPHIC DESIGN | Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign, GIMP, digital and print ad design, printed newsletter design, document layout design

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Marketing Cloud Email Specialist Salesforce, 2024

Email Marketer HubSpot Academy, 2023

#### **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Arts: Organizational Communication for Consulting & Research, Minor: Marketing Lipscomb University — 2011

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior Email & SMS Developer

Promoted from Digital Media & Web Developer in June 2024

Precept Ministries International — Chattanooga, Tennessee (Remote) December 2019 - PRESENT

#### **Email Marketing**

- Subject matter expert for Salesforce Marketing Cloud
- Built 750+ unique and performant HTML emails
- Designed, implemented, and maintain customer journeys
- Detected web form weaknesses and identified thousands of bot accounts for removal
- Launched and warmed a new email IP

#### Frontend Web Development

- Developed new web components for fundraising campaigns
- Designed and developed layout and components for a new Shopify homepage

#### Content Management

- Train and mentor the Digital Content Platform Specialist in technical skills and content management
- Provide guidance to team members for project delivery and prioritization, maintain process and technical documentation
- Led content migration and development projects leading up to a brand relaunch

#### **Analytics & Data**

- Created SQL automations to pull complex data reports
- Transitioned six web properties to Google Analytics 4
- Redefined how the organization tracks web engagement and wrote custom tracking scripts

# **Brandon Caples**

#### SENIOR DIGITAL MARKETER

(423) 281-5150 brandon.caples@gmail.com brandoncaples.com







### Web Content Specialist

Mercy Multiplied America — Nashville, Tennessee

April 2018 - December 2019

I maintained website code and content, designed page layouts, optimized for search engines, and managed digital ads.

- Planned email campaigns, coded HTML emails, wrote email copy, and designed graphic assets
- Created and maintained event registrations and donation forms
- Revived a dead blog and developed its content plan for blog authors
- Designed and developed new content directories for mercymultiplied.com

### Digital Marketing Specialist

Columbia Coatings, LLC — Columbia, Tennessee

June 2017 - February 2018

I managed all email marketing, created website content, designed marketing graphics, and trained new associates for phone sales.

- Managed concept, design, and implementation of weekly email newsletter
- Retouched product photos and collected customer product photos
- Managed 4,000+ ecommerce products and general website performance
- Wrote, directed, and edited product tutorial videos

## Director of Client Communications, Deering Wealth Team

Southwestern Investment Group — Franklin, Tennessee

January 2016 - June 2017

I designed and launched a new website, wrote for the financial blog, coordinated client events, managed social media, and designed business collateral.

- Wrote and designed email communications, event collateral, website content, and blog posts
- Designed and launched deeringwealthteam.com
- Wrote, directed, and edited financial planning videos
- Planned, coordinated, and promoted client events and seminars

## Marketing Director

Batson Chiropractic Group — Nashville, Tennessee

August 2013 - January 2016

Wrote for blogs and the print newsletter, managed social media, and designed marketing collateral, among other duties.

- Oversaw ~60% business growth over 2½ years
- Increased monthly new patient average by 25.9% over previous two years •
- Grew Facebook following by 267%
- Designed and launched nashvillebraincore.com
- Automated the new patient intake process, avoiding human error and time costs during intake
- Designed marketing collateral, including website content, direct mail, newsletters, signage, email graphics, ads, etc.
- Developed email customer journeys